Guide to the Ramdasha Bikceem Riot Grrrl Collection 1974-1998 (Bulk 1991-1995) MSS.354
Fales Library and Special Collections
Ramdasha Bikceem Riot Grrrl Collection
1974-1998
1991-1995
Fales Library and Special Collections
Bikceem, Ramdasha
MSS.354
3.25 Linear Feet (7 Boxes)
Ramdasha Bikceem is a New York City DJ and vintage clothing store owner, and was a zine writer while she was a teenager, in the early 1990s. In her zine GUNK, Bikceem wrote about her girl skater gang and band of the same name, as well as on topics of race, feminism, youth angst, and the lack of diversity in the Riot Grrrl movement. The Ramdasha Bikceem Riot Grrrl Collection includes zines, zine masters, flyers, comics, correspondence, photos, media stills, and audiovisual material associated with Bikceem's participation in the punk and Riot Grrrl movements as both a writer and zine collector.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series:
1. Series I: Zines
2. Series II: Ephemera and Correspondence
3. Series III: Video
The subseries within Series I represent Bikceem's own arrangement and categorizations. Materials within series and subseries are arranged alphabetically.
Scope and Content
The Ramdasha Bikceem Riot Grrrl Collection consists of zines, zine masters, comics, ephemera, flyers, catalogues, photos, media stills, correspondence, and media.The collection documents Bikceem's participation in the Riot Grrrl movement. A majority of the collection is comprised of Bikceem's personal collection of zines (bulk 1992-1996) and materials from her own zine, GUNK.
This collection is divided into 3 series:
Series I: Zines: This series comprises Bikceem's collection of zines related to punk and the Riot Grrrl Movement. It also includes materials pertaining to Bikceem's own zine, GUNK. It is further divided into seven subseries that were designated by Bikceem:
Subseries A: General Zines
Subseries B: Feminist Zines
Subseries C: Larger Zines
Subseries D: Dude Zines
Subseries E: Mini Zines
Subseries F: Unidentified Zines
Subseries G: GUNK
Series II: Ephemera and Correspondence: This series contains flyers, comics, catalogues, and correspondence (bulk 1992-1995). It is further divided into two subseries:
Subseries A: Ephemera
Subseries B: Correspondence
Series III: Video: This series contains 2 VHS casettes, "A Cinezine by K8 Hardy" and "[Frenchified lifestyle]."
Biographical Note
Ramdasha Bikceem grew up in New Jersey, where she started writing a fanzine in 1990, when she was 15 years old. She was inspired by an older friend who had lived next door to Tobi Vail of Bikini Kill, who brought her copies of Girl Germs and Bikini Kill zines. These fanzines inspired her to start her own zine named GUNK. It mostly focused on her skater girl gang and band of the same name. Through this zine she connected with Kathleen Hanna, Johanna Fateman, and other seminal figures in the Riot Grrrl scene. She travelled to Olympia, Washington, and later her band performed at the first Riot Grrrrl convention in 1992 in Washington D.C.
Bikceem completed five issues of her zine, which focused on topics of race, feminism and general youth angst. Particularly in the last few issues of Gunk, Ramdasha wrote about the lack of diversity within the scene, and expressed her opinions around racial dilemmas and class conflicts within the Riot Grrrl movement.
In 1993 she moved to Brooklyn, where she attended Pratt University. She currently lives in New York City where she DJs and makes music. She also runs a online vintage clothing store called Klub Kid Vintage.
Provenance
The Ramdasha Bikceem Riot Grrrl Collection was donated to NYU's Fales Library by Ramdasha Bikceem in 2012.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Zines; Fanzines.; Riot grrrl movement.; Videocassettes.; Correspondence.; Teenage girls.; Fliers (printed matter); Comic books.; Punk rock music.; Racism.; Feminism; Skateboarding.; Bikceem, Ramdasha
- Series I: Zines
  Scope and Content
  Series I: Zines: This series comprises Bikceem's collection of zines related to punk and the Riot Grrrl Movement. It also includes materials pertaining to Bikceem's own zine, GUNK.
  - Subseries A: General Zines
    - AAHDD, [1994] (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Artaud-Mania, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bagel Quest, [1996] (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bantha Fodder, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Blow Your Mind, [1994] (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Catherine's hair, [1995], undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Channel Seven, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chatterbox, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Chocolate Impulse, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - The Colour of Shadow, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Copper Beech, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - D.A.M., [1992] (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Daggy Madeline, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Double Bill, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Drum Core, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Ea, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Erreakzoia-reaccion, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Eureka/Arcata Riot Grrrls, [1994] (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Fists of Fury, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Freak Mama, [1994] (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - G is for Girl, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Holy titclamps, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - I wake up cuz I have stopped breathing, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - I'm Not Having Garbonzo Beans, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Jank, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - The Jigsaw, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Abstract
      Bikini Kill drummer Tobi Vail's riot grrrl fanzine issue number 5 1/2 opens with frustration surrounding the ennui and repetitiveness of small town life, which is a motivation for the zine itself. Local news includes an anecdote about violence against women in music. Plans for Bikini Kill and a piece on the band's meaning follows. The bulk of the zine is dedicated to extensive live and recorded music and zine news and reviews, excerpted song lyrics, and addresses for inquiry and distribution. Also contains an original cartoon.
    - Jing Bang So, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Kingfish, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Kissy Kissy (the Creep Issue), undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Little Girl, [1994] (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Molasses Soulkiss, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - MTM, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - My need to speak on the subject of Jackson Pollock, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Nerd Girl, [1994] (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Never Revere, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Pixie Girl, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Plain Jane, [1994] (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Pretty Shield, [1996] (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Private Catholic, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Prone to Fall, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Purge, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Recess Records, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Reticence and Anxiety, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Riot Geeek!, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - [riot Pro-Teen], undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Risk, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Salsa Amoeba, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Sandbox Brats, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Satan Wears a Bra, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Silly, [1993] (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Size 9 1/2, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Skagboy, [1994] (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Smile for Me, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Starfucker, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - ...sometimes i'm a pretty girl, [1994] (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Southern Hysteria, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Square One, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Subterranean Mailorder, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Such is Life, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Tease, 1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Too Far, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Ultramodern, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Winkypinky, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - words and smiles, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Wow Cool, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Y(our) Ass + My Face, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Subseries B: Feminist Zines
    - Crusade, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - HAPPYLAND, [1991, 1992] (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Knotwork, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Live Beat, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Rocktober, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - TRUSTKILL, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Weird City, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: Larger Zines
    - Agra, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - All Hail the Nuns, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Attitude Problem, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Bruce On A Stick, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Chainletter, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Eat Me!, [1994] (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Evacuation Day, [1993] (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Feminine Napkins, [1994] (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Fenceclimber, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Fiat Lux, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Grit, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Grot Grrrl, [1993] (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - I Hate Valentine's Day!, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - K Records, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Modern Shaman, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Monsters Unleashed!, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Mousie, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Plunger, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Rock Fight, [1994] (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Rock 'N Roll High School Newsletter, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Shrill, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Skunk, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Slug and Lettuce, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Super Star Forever, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Switch Hitter, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Teenage Gang Debs, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Teenage Suicide, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Tooth Fairy, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Toxic Shock, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - TWB, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Virus, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Wiglet, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Subseries D: Dude Zines
    - The Adventures of Absolutely Zippo!, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - annoyance, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - bobby is fred, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Boredom, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Boy Does High School Ever Suck, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - COMETBUS, 1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Dishwasher, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - The dissonant accost, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Fuck Tooth, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Gizzard Gazette, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - I HATE YOU, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - LA COSTRA, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Pants that Don't Fit, [1993], [1995], undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - PHLOX, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Pocho, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Pook, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Reasonably Martian's, [1994] (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - SILVULLINEN, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Sticks and Stones, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Subseries E: Mini Zines
    - BLEMISH, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Christy Sprite, [1993] (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Cow/boy Love, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Cubbyhole, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - The Diane Files, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Graham Cracker Cereal, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Guilt, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - half-life, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Impress Your Friends, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - It Grosses Her Out, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - The Jimmy Saga, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Mickey Rourke, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - SOURPUSS, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Subseries F: Unidentified Zines
    - Unidentified Zines, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Subseries G: GUNK
    - GUNK Masters, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - GUNK #4 Original Master, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - GUNK #4 Complete Copy, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - GUNK #4 Incomplete Copies, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - GUNK #5 [Incomplete], 1994 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - GUNK Ephemera, 1992, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Photos and Media Stills, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Series II: Ephemera and Correspondence
  Series II: Ephemera and Correspondence: This series contains flyers, comics, catalogues, and correspondence (bulk 1992-1995).
  - Subseries A: Ephemera
    - Activism (Flyers, etc), 1993-1997, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Dirty Plotte [comic], 1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Hate [comic], 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Mail Order Catalogs, 1993, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Mini Flyers, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Naughty Bits [comic], 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Tank Girl 2 [comic], 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B: Correspondence
    Series II: Suberies B inlcudes correspondence sent to Bikceem from people asking for zines, responding to the contents of GUNK, or sending their own zines.
    - Andrew, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Badger, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Bean, Chris, 1992, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Brat, Allison, 1992, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Christina, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - D, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Difference, Sam, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Droogas, Adrienne, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Emcee, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Enriquez, Denise, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Grace, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Greenwood, Wynne, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Griff, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Habe-Evans, Mito, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Hanna, Kathleen, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Harris, Selwyn, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Ian, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Jane, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Janelle/Olga, 1993, 1994, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Joaquin, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - John, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Josh, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Khourey, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Kim, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Mike, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Mindy, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Morris, Maggie, 1996, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Murphy, Lori, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Nick, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Padrino, Laura, 1993, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Pariah, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Rivera, Mabel, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Robert, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Sandra, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Theo, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Vail, Tobi, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Unknown Correspondence, 1995, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Series III: Video
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - A Cinezine by K8 Hardy, [1997-1998]; 354.0001 (Box 7, Cassette 354.0001, E-records fales_mss354, E-records 354.0001)
    3 videos made by K8 Hardy: [1]--"This Red Envelope" [2]--"Believe Me" [3]--"A Little Off"
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    VHS, 15 min.
  - [Frenchified lifestyle], undated; 354.0002 (Box 7, Cassette 354.0002, E-records fales_mss354, E-records 354.0002)
    VHS, 29 min.